KAYLA

MARTINEZ

kaylaann88@gmail.com

(689) 247-7928

Daytona Beach, FL 32124

Linkedin

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data Analyst with a background in marketing, market research, business operations, and management. Skilled at identifying the root of any problem and fixing it quickly. Trained in adapting my communication style to every individual's needs. Developed strategies to maintain production cost and budget needs.

SKILLS

- Python
- SOL
- pandas
- Aloha
- Excel
- GitHub
- Quickbooks
- Wix
- Branding
- Budget development
- Analytical
- Microsoft Suite
- Leadership
- Marketing
- Networking
- Problem solving
- Public Speaking
- Critical thinking
- Pricing structures
- Research methods
- Market Analysis
- Employee training

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry
Online • 12/2022

Data Analysis

Western Michigan University Kalamazoo MI • 05/2015

Bachelor's: Marketing

· Graduated magna cum laude

University of Iowa Italy

CIMBA Leadership Program, Italy: Study Abroad

- Graduated magna cum laude
- Received Resident Advisor Scholarship
- Yoga Instructor and Mindfulness Coordinator for Students

WORK HISTORY

Applebee's Bar and Grill - Restaurant Manager

Orange City, FL 08/2021 - Current

- Gathered, analyze and draw practical conclusions from data, as well as communicate data findings to team members.
- Proficiency in statistical data analysis over employee goals and standards
- Built strong relationships with vendors in order to accommodate demand while staying within budget.
- Measured the progress of staff members as they complete their training programs as well as promotions within the store.

Mellow Mushroom - Manager

Port Orange, Florida • 7/2020 - 8/2021

- Successfully managed and motivated a 35-member team, reducing the staff turnover to 2% from 35%
- Built relations with guests and external professional relations, provided support in all areas including customer queries.
- Inventory management cost tracking.
- Managed bar inventory, restocked supplies and placed orders for spirits, beer, wines and mixers.
- Upsold daily specials and beverage promotions to exceed daily sales goals.

Fifth Avenue Bar and Grille - Bar Manager Daytona Beach, Florida • 03/2012 - 10/2016

- Maintain high professionalism with each guest and working to build a positive rapport while also striving to reach daily and weekly goals, Alcohol budget development and cost tracking
- Capitalized on opportunities to advance operations and mixology knowledge, enhancing customer service with refined and current expertise.
- Implemented quality control initiatives while creating house-made cocktails, juice and preparations to reduce downtime and increase revenue.

Kamili Athletic Wear - Marketing Coordinator

Kalamazoo, MI • 01/2019 - Current

- Develop marketing concepts through branding, design, communication, and networking.
- Helped incorporate product changes to drive customer engagement and firm profits.
- Leveraged different market research strategies to investigate new products and enhance campaign planning.